Harry Hanan Papers
Harry Hanan Papers
1947-1966
Hanan, Harry, 1916-1982
2 linear ft.
Original daily cartoons and proofs from the newspaper comic strip Louie, correspondence, photographs, and clippings.
149030
Biographical History
Cartoonist Harry Hanan (1916-1982) was born in Liverpool, England on December 14, 1916. He was educated in England and from 1936-1940 was employed as an editorial cartoonist for the Liverpool Evening Express. His syndicated newspaper comic strip Louie ran from 1947 until Hanan's retirement in 1976. Harry Hanan died in 1982.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harry Hanan Papers consists of cartoons, clippings, correspondence, photographs, and proofs.
Cartoons contains original artwork for the comic strip Louie, more than 120 daily strips from 1953 to 1964. Artwork is graphite, zipatone, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 4 ¾ x 17 ½ in.
Clippings contains newspaper and magazine clippings about Hanan and his work, including a few family photos.
Correspondence is primarily from readers of the strip.
Photographs contains a formal portrait of Hanan as well as a family photo.
Proofs consists of proof sheets from the comic strip Louie between 1964 and 1966. There are 6 daily strips per newsprint sheet.
Arrangement of the Collection
Materials are sorted by type and arranged in chronological order.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Hanan, Harry, 1916-1982.; Chicago Tribune-New York News Syndicate.; Louie (comic strip); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Proofs (printed matter); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Harry Hanan, 1966 and 1970.
One item, an original strip dated 7/20/64, gift of Dilts and Koester, Attorneys at Law, in memory of their client William Devine, 2020.
Inventory
- Louie daily comic strips, 285
  Click here for detailed inventory.
  - Original cartoons, 1953 Sep - 1964 Dec; 129 (Box 1)
    Original strip dated 7/20/64, gift of Dilts & Koester law firm in memory of their client William Devine, 2020.
  - Proofs, 1964 Nov - 1966 Sep; 27 proof sheets x 6 comic strips per sheet (Box 1)
- Clippings
  - Miscellaneous, about Hanan and his work, 1947-1950 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming correspondence from readers, 1947-1963 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Hanan family, Nov 1948; handwritten note on back: "the Hanan's arrive in the States" (Box 1)
  - Portrait of Hanan, undated (Box 1)